SMITH KAMLESH GAJJAR

Mumbai, Maharashtra

smith.gajjar@gmail.com www.smithgajjar.dev smith-gajjar smithg09

Senior Full Stack Developer and Solutions Architect with over 2.5 years of experience in startups, building applications and open source projects using several languages and JavaScript frameworks, managing and optimizing backend infrastructure including deployment, scalability, performance and 3rd party service integrations.

EXPERIENCE

Tekie [₹ Senior Full Stack Developer

June 2022 - Present

Remote

Full Stack Developer

June 2021 - June 2022

Frontend Developer Intern

Feb 2021 - June 2021

- Tekie is a B2B Ed-tech platform that uses storytelling to make learning to code a movie-like experience. As a core team member collaborated and scaled platform to over 500+ schools.
- Developed user facing modules, a PWA based on **Reactis** and **Redux** and a Desktop App using **Electron.is**. Optimized Landing Page Score/Performance and SEO to 99% to improve visibility and Core Web Vitals.
- Developed, Managed and Optimized API and backend architecture for enhanced scalability and performance, reducing response time by over 60% utilizing Node.js, GraphQL, MongoDB, Redis and CDN Caching.
- Developed and Managed Internal Reports and tooling architecture for Business Team utilizing Node.js, ETL Process (From MongoDB to SQL), PostgreSQL and Python (Flask) for data-driven decisions.
- Integrated different 3rd party services such as GSuit, Newrelic, Sentry, Elastic Search, Stellate (GraphQL Caching) and **GA/GTM/Looker Studio** to improve and monitor application performance.
- Managed and Optimized DevOps infrastructure and Configured CI/CD on Github/Jenkins based of Kubernetes, Redis, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Azure Services and AWS Services such as EC2, EKS, ECR, S3, Elastic Transcoder and CloudFront.
- Developed and Contributed to open-source NPM libraries for the platform, mongodb-aggregation-builder, tekie-content-editor, tekie-blockly. Developed and Led many Proof of Concept's for Product Development.
- Interacting and engaging in discussions with stakeholders from various departments to determine and deliver optimal tech solutions aligned with business requirements.
- Mentored, Guided and led a team of 7 in spearheading the product development and seamless migration of an product suite. Encouraged code hygiene and best practices while building along with peer code reviews.

InVideo [₹

Mumbai June 2019 - July 2019

Front-end Developer Intern

- InVideo is an best rated online professional video editing SaaS Platform with over 7M+ users.
- Built new user facing modules by converting designs from Sketch and InVision into pixel-perfect and responsive screens using Angular 7, HTML, SCSS and TypeScript.
- Helped in fixing cross-browser inconsistencies in the interface using **BrowserStack**.

PROJECTS

mongodb-aggregation-builder 🗗

• MongoDB Aggregation Pipeline Builder NPM Library built using Typescript.

GraphQL Nodejs Backend Starter

• A Typesafe NodeJS Backend Server Boilerplate/Starter Built using Typescript/MongoDB/GraphQL/Redis.

Blockly NPM Library 🔀

• Customised Blockly React Wrapper around Google's official Blockly Library.

View all projects n smithg09

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages/Frameworks: JavaScript, Python, SQL, NoSQL, NodeJS, GraphQL, ReactJS, Angular, TypeScript, Redis, NGINX, Electron, HTML, CSS/Sass, React Native., Next.js, Redux. Databases: MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL

Tools: AWS, Azure, Sentry, Jenkins, Git, Webpack, Notion, Vercel, Docker, Jest, Jira, Trello, Looker Studio, GA/GTM

EDUCATION

Vivekanand Educational Society's Institute of Technology

2018 - 2021

2015 - 2018

Bachelor Of Engineering In Computer Science

Mumbai, Maharashtra

K.J.Somaiya Polytechnic

Diploma In Computer Engineering

Mumbai, Maharashtra